我哋應該夠call啦，我哋就先請官員。
入職先。
係啊。
早晨，各位就因為時間到啦，亦都我哋夠我哋嘅足夠參加會議嘅人數。
亦都首先歡迎今日誒嚟出席嘅。
誒各位官員，有財經事務及顧務。
局首席助理秘書。
助理秘書長啊，廖生。
有金管局嘅銀行政策嘅簡嘉蘭女士。
有金管局嘅。
銀行政策嘅豬生。
仲有就係。
律政司、政府律師吳生。
律政司高級助理法律草擬專員林生同埋金管局嘅高級經理銀行政策邱女士。
好啊！我哋先歡迎各位就。
今日就繼續係作為第二次嘅小組委員會嘅會議。
咁咧就喺。
上一次會議。
之後，我哋係咪需要？
對上一次會議誒提出嗰啲事項咧，誒跟進一下，就係上一次會議咧就同誒委員同意再邀請呢個銀行業。
諮詢委員會以及接受存款公司諮詢委員會。
入香港有限制牌照銀行及接受存款公司、公會以及。
銀行公會啊，呢以上嘅咁多個機構咧。
就提供呢個書面意見嘅，對於三項嘅附屬法例嘅。
回應意見，噉啊，有關機構咧嘅回覆就已經跟隨立法會畀我哋一個文件，係CB一一七五十二、Ivan一三零一至零三嘅文件咧，發畀我哋各位委員㗎啦。我相信大家已經備悉咗有關文件嘅。
噉啊！
有關文件咧就收之外咧，我亦都誒喺度表達一下咧，就係因為銀行界方面嘅一啲誒意見咧，就提供咗畀本人。
就佢哋有留意到呢個。
有所謂叫發達國家對呢個誒二零一三年一月一號實施巴塞爾。
誒誒，依個協議三嘅依個有關嘅實施有言嘅一啲報道，咁咧就所以有有機構咧就反映就係話銀誒英國嘅金融服務局FSA。
喺一二年。
八月一號咧，就發表個聲明，表示英國冇可能喺。
二零一三年一月一號推行巴塞爾三。
之後咧，美國嘅聯儲局同埋聯邦存款保險公司，以及貨幣管理局咧，喺十一月九號，即係今年十一月九號咧，亦都發表個聯合公告，表示收到業界大量唔同意見。
所以咧，不期待喺一三年一月一號實施呢個新協定。
咁呢個咧就係因為本港嘅業界咧都關注到呢啲問題，所以咧就透過我亦都反映一下話：，如果如果我哋誒要實施嘅話，亦都唔應該係成為第一批或者早於呢啲誒地區或者國家實施嘅。
作為一個誒帶頭者，依個提法，咁所以我喺度咧代表業界咧先反映咗依個意見先，唔知政府方面有冇咩特別嘅回應咧？
啊，兩生很得意。
我請金管局啊，邊間業先再講，OK？我唔係，我請金管局啊，啊，金管局嗰方面再講。
因為。
感謝你。Thank, thank you, Chairman. First of all, I would note that the Basel Committee itself has not changed its implementation date for the first phase of Basel III. That remains the 1st of January 2012.
其他亞洲 regulator's are poised to go ahead on the 1st of January 2013. Sorry, I said 2012. I meant 2013. So, for instance, Singapore has issued its rules, Australia has issued its rules, the mainland has issued its rules. So
jurisdictions are moving towards the 1st of January 2013 date. We are aware that the US announced on the 9th of November that there would be some delay in the US.
然而，在其宣佈中，美國小心地提及他們非常重視其國際時限承諾，並正在迅速地完成其規則制定權力。美國已經經過巴爾茲委員會的二級評估。
所以它的通知有提出的規則制定，和它的提出規則已經審查過合規性，和報告所發表的報告顯示，有高程度的合規性與巴薩爾三。所以美國正在穩健地朝巴薩爾三的實施。在銀行持有的資本方面，即使巴薩爾三。
is not actually in place in the U.S. The large banks that are included in the Federal Reserve's stress testing programme.
Must show an ability to hold Tier One common risk-based capital akin to CET One under Basel III of five. So even though Basel III is not in force as such, the banks in the US are moving towards the position where they will be in line with Basel III, and also on the.
9號11月，美國宣佈2013年壓力測試計劃，所以這個過程將會繼續進行。
For the EU, again, we are aware that there is some delay. There is a political process to be undertaken within the EU, and there is a tria log discussion going on between the Parliament, the Commission and the EU Council. On the 13th of November, it seems.
that there was a meeting of the council for economic and financial affairs, where they discussed CRD IV, which is the EU version of Basel III.
And there was a press release that referred to a commitment to reach an agreement with the Parliament before the end of the year. So I think they still intend to reach political agreement on CRD IV within this year, and then it will be a question of implementation next year. It's obvious.
Obviously not possible on the 31st of December to make an agreement and have the banks implement immediately from the 1st of January. So there will be a lead-in time. But so far as we are aware, both the EU and the US are moving towards Basel III implementation.
嘅。
好，阿田議員。
你你，你，主席話。
sorry，我係有個bad throat。If in the states and in like UK。
They're not going to implement it on the first part of 2013.
then if we implement it, then most of our banks have relationship or actually are part of the banks in New York and London.
then how would that particular multinational bank operate?
如果唔有，有香港。
I assume that will be a subsidiary of, let's say.
a larger of a large bank just.
I guess we're not supposed to use names, but then the bank that's headquartered in London or New York, if they're not implementing it yet.
and we're doing it. How does that particular bank's internal management?
comply to that, or are we saying that it doesn't really matter? We could do it first because we're doing a better job, so we do it first.
and they could follow suit later. I guess one answer must be that if an international bank have like 40 branches around the world, what the countries have to do at first. So someone will have to start doing it.
and if they all do it and the UK or London, New York does it later, they will have trouble implementing it. But I guess the chairman's question is maybe a lot of Hong Kong.
people would ask why do we want to be ahead of New York or London? After all, they're still the leading financial market in the world. I'm just talking New York, London, and seems the chairman said that.
Both London and New York will not be implementing it full steam ahead. Ah, full steam ahead on.
January thirty first, could we at least go at the same pace as London, New York, and not be ahead of them? And if we do it ahead of them, are there any advantage to us? Maybe reputation-wise, you could say we're leading New York and London, but other than that, in real terms, are there any benefits?
呃，幹得先。Thank you, Chairman.
Again, I would reiterate that the delay in the US and the EU is due to the circumstances prevailing there. The international regulatory reform efforts spearheaded by the FSB and the Basel Committee set the 1st of January 2013 as the timetable. So as
Members of the Basel Committee, the FSB, and working towards strengthening the financial system, the global financial system, following the crisis.
We are committed to the one st of January two thousand and thirteen. We actually think that Basel three is useful. That the crisis showed that banks did not have enough capital, so therefore strengthening the resilience of banks. But with an extended time frame for implementation.
Implementation to enable them to support sustainable economic development seems to us to be the most balanced way of proceeding.
And so, for that reason, we we propose, as as as far as we are aware, other other Asian regulators that are perhaps better placed to to meet the standards to proceed.
所以，議長，我覺得答案是。
嗯。
In E U, they are not ready implement. The main reason is the capital ratio.
And if the point is that our banks is in such a good condition or better condition under our internal rules of HKMA, we are all in a position to do that. As the letter from HK, sorry, Hong Kong Association of Banks.
said that since we're meeting the criteria anyway, then we could do it without much trouble.
while if they can do it because of their capital ratio, then it's up to them. If we're not ready, then we have a problem. Since we're ready, then we're saying that why don't we do it first? So is that the main difference between EU and the states? The fact they cannot comply at all?
January two or one three is because of singly one items the capital issue.
I think that's certainly a large contributing factor. I think there are some other factors at play. So, for instance, for the US, they put out their consultation first in June, so it was relatively late. The reason being that they have to deal with the Dodd Frank Act. Now, Basel, but the
巴塞爾資本監管框架使用外部評級，對於一些的措施。
The Dodd Frank Act actually prohibits the US regulators from using external ratings again, largely because of what happened in the crisis, where the ratings for very certain products were not found to perform as expected. So, in the US, if you like, they have to form their own version.
of Basel III, in compliance with the Dodd Frank Act. So the complexity of that, plus the fact that resource-wise, they're producing hundreds and hundreds of sets of rules under Dodd Frank.
has has inevitably slowed them down. So they they began, I think, consulting in June. They extended the consultation period until towards the end of October. So so they've just got the comments back. So so so they have a sort of a volume of work and a deal of complexity to deal with. Again, in the EU.
There was some concerns over the summer about the way the EU have decided to do a single rule book.
So Basel standards are usually well are a minimum. In the EU, they decided to try to make sure that individual members did not go above that minimum in order to sort of conform the single rule across the EU. Some jurisdictions were very vociferous in their objection to that, including the UK, Sweden.
所以，他們 had to come to a compromise solution on that over the summer.
I understand also that for some reason within their their capital requirement they have bonus restrictions which have nothing to do with the capital but have gone into there. So there's a political element to that. So I think all of these combined factors, plus frankly the fact that they're working on banking union as well at the same time, have have sort of
slowed down the process in the EU. So again, they have competing demands upon them that are coming into it. So capital is one thing, but there are, I think, some surrounding factors that are also militating towards delay.
主席，如果 members are not have have any specific question to ask yet， may I continue with two short ones？ Okay， two short ones。 The first one is we have two submissions， is the DTCSC Association and the Hong Kong Association of Banks。
We have two copies. Are we saying that when we want to get the industry's view, these are the two main.
sort of associations that's related to this whole Basel three.
呃。
arrangements and there's no further association that might have a view that we had not written for them for view or they had not responded. These are the the two major two's. Yes, these are the the two major two's. And then on HK.
Association banks. It seems their reply is a bit longer. They are saying, for example, in paragraph two, in general, we are supportive of the principle of that topic. It seems they they use the word supportive, use the word principle.
呃，for you to see， reinforce Hong Kong position， then the。
bottom of that page，they say between different banks，according to the individual circumstances，such as size，financial position。
business and group nature, it seems they do think that even if we do it in Hong Kong now, you have to base on
啲事。
blah blah blah，then some will have an easier time complying with it. Some maybe have a difficult time complying it. So our position be that once this is set up, we do give them a sort of a grace period. I don't know six months, nine months, so that the big banks that miss all these will have an easier time to do it, and the other ones will have a chance to do it. Or will you say that?
如果佢哋唔 meet the by certain deadline， in certain clauses，佢會被penalised。
We've been talking to the banks for a long time on Basel III, and they have already capital plan capital planning arrangements. So they have been working towards compliance with these the content of this set of rules with effect from.
從一月一號二零一三年，我認為HCB所説的點是，可能有銀行間的差異。如果銀行有大額的衍生品交易，就會受到這些新收費的影響。如果銀行的資本基數有問題，
Less common equity, then you may need you may be looking to raise more common equity. Although with Hong Kong banks, they tend to hold a lot of common equity, so the new common equity tier one ratio should not be a problem for them.
好，啊。
兩年。
多謝主席。
perhaps I would also follow up on the letter from the Hong Kong Association of Banks.
It seems that.
They are making.
兩個非常有趣的點，但係我唔明白點解會喺實踐中運作。
The first point that they made is the one under.
Para two.
Well, they made the point that they believe it is imperative.
that a level regulatory playing field is created.
And that the Brussels III proposals are implemented globally.
Over the page.
They are saying, top of the page.
對，這。
第二線，我們也注意到，作為諮詢過程的一部分，香港MA已承擔監察《巴塞爾III》實施進展在其他主要管轄區，例如歐盟和美國，以確保沒有對香港機構的競爭優勢。
嗱。
perhaps the chairman can also enlighten me on this. What if
作為結果，的監察過程。
Some banks or the Hong Kong Association of Banks as a whole.
comes to the view that by implementing Basel III in Hong Kong on 1st January 2013.
會place Hong Kong banks。
in a disadvantage.
when competing with EU banks and US banks.
And they are not satisfied that a level regulatory playing field is being created.
can they be exempted?
from compliance with the rules that we are making today. Thank you, chairman.
講住先。
多謝主席。
嗯。
No, they won't be exempted from compliance. But so you are correct. No, what we've said to the Hong Kong Association of Banks, as the consultation process has unfolded, is that we will monitor the way in which implementation takes place in other jurisdictions. So, as we discussed last time, you have the bars.
文本，但每個司法管轄區必須將其轉譯成自己的法律框架，所以。
Sometimes in that transposition, changes may be made. We've made a few ourselves that we've outlined. Other jurisdictions may do the same, and we would be interested to see if any of those changes materially change the effect of Basel III on their banks.
所以它是一個持續的過程。所以我們一直在看巴爾茲委員會本身在美國和歐盟就他們對《草案》規則的合規性評估所做的工作。而當最終規則發布時，將會有後續的跟進。
It's an ongoing process. It's not necessarily the case that if the EU changes something, then we would automatically follow suit. We will consider what is suitable in Hong Kong, whether it's a major disadvantage, whether from a prudential concern we think we should still stick to the Basel III principle, or whether we should.
We should introduce some flexibility.
Follow-up. I think this is the point that the honourable James Tean has been following.
It seems that the Hong Kong Association of Banks is a bit worried.
That by compliance.
啊！
with the rules that we are making today.
Would somehow?
put our best
in a disadvantaged position when competing with other banks, for example in the US and in the EU, globally. That's why they are making the point under para two that there had to be a level regulatory playing field.
If compliance means
香港 banks are being penalised, then of course we as legislators are concerned that we should not put our banks in a disadvantaged position. My question and I think similar question from the honourable James Tean, whether that would turn out to be the case, that is our worry.
I think we we should.
Remember to some extent why why we're doing what we're doing.
The crisis showed that the existing system, the Basel II system, allowed banks to operate with less capital than it turned out that they needed. Times had moved on, banking had changed, and banks were running perhaps more risk than the existing capital system.
was designed to support. So,
作為結果，的危機，它一般都同意銀行需要持有更多和更佳品質的資本。
但 whilst in a crisis situation, you could make the crisis worse if you implement everything immediately and say, in a perfect world, this is what I want. Now, now, now, do this. So, so the Basel III process is is designed to be a balance. It's designed to raise the the level and quality of banks' capital, which we think is a good thing.
It's designed to do this over an extended implementation period, so that that does not the raising of the new capital, the new standards do not impede upon banks' normal credit intermediation activities. So we think Basel III is a good thing. So it's not something that we are just following because everybody else is following. We think.
好。
And so we think our banks should should should should be moving towards this. And I think they think the same in the in the EU and in the US. It is just that they are unfortunately delayed by other issues.
that that are affecting their jurisdictions, which were indeed the jurisdictions worst affected by the crisis.
gentleman, with your permission.
I think we are talking across purposes here.
嗯。
呵。
呃，the of course I。
我 understand fully what Miss Kemp is trying to tell us.
That this is for the good of everybody.
That the Basel Three more stringent requirements of capital standards etc. should be applied to the banks in Hong Kong.
但， chairman， I must first confess that I'm no expert in banking operation. The chairman certainly is.
但，它似乎從那封信，我們正在看，日期為15號11月，來自香港銀行協會。
They are worried.
作為專家在銀行運作。
That a level regulatory playing field may not be created on the 1st of January 2013, and from the point that I read to you, Ms. Kemp.
Over the page on page two of their letter, it seems that they are envisaging a situation.
That investors.
may decide to go somewhere else than Hong Kong, because those places.
在那些地方，他們的銀行並未被要求要達到巴塞爾三最 stringent 標準，所以作為一個投資者決定在哪個市場或哪個
banks in which market to go to.
for investment purposes, for what they want to achieve.
They may take advantage of this window of difference.
Between the regulatory framework.
In Hong Kong, which is parcel free compliant.
and some.
其他 markets。
Where banks are not yet required to live up to the Basel III standard, I think the point that worries us.
And apparently.
The Hong Kong Association of Banks.
what's that point?
Chairman, I don't think that point has been addressed. I think, from an investor point of view, the stronger the bank, the better. So I think that I think it would almost go the other way that if you haven't implemented Basel standards and your banks are perceived to be weaker, they might find it more difficult.
在吸引投資者，所以從從的點的觀點，銀行的資金，可能有優勢在採用更嚴格的標準。
主席，我我唔 pretend to be expert here。如果香港社會的banks is only prepared to go
as far as what we are reading in the letter 15th of November 2002, then I would rest my case here.
對，呃，新月。嗯，Mr. Chairman， I'm reading news. Here it says the Basel III could be finalised. Basel III could be finalised in December. Says you know, separate finance ministers.
啊，what the news啊？
我學過是，你知唔知歐洲財政部長還在討論一些規則。
So I think I just want to echo some of my, you know, the points raised by some of our colleagues. It seems that even the U.S. Treasury is saying, you know, they are not implementing Basel III on one st of January two thousand and fifteen. So does so do many of the European countries. So
Could you tell me, to be more exact?
you know what kind what countries will be ready will be implementing on first of January and see if we need to follow suit.
嗯，你知唔知？我諗啊，The banks are subtly saying，你知唔知？We we would like to comply，但冇 need to hurry。That's the message that I read through lines of the letter.
Thank you. Okay, Australia has issued its its final rules to take effect on the 1st of January. Mainland China has issued its final rules to take effect on the 1st of January. India has issued its final rules to take effect on the 1st of January. Japan has issued its final rules to take effect on the 1st of January.
Singapore has issued final rules to take effect on 1st of January. Switzerland has issued final rules to take effect on 1st of January. Canada directed its banks in February 2011 to meet the new CET1 standard as of 1st of January.
所以那些 ones 我們知道是 definite。
啊！
Korea, we know, issued a draft regulation in September 2012.
And I think Indonesia is still consulting. On, they they issued a draft in June 2012. May I focus on several countries like UK?
啊，The U.S. have fears for you know more exact timetable. How about Germany?
These three big countries, for example. Okay, the the UK and Germany are obviously bound by the EU timetable in the sense that they will implement in their jurisdictions CRD IV, the European Directive Capital Requirement Directive. So it's difficult for them to implement before CRD IV is.
is finalised. So they're bundling with the European Union. Yes. So, but having having said that, both of those, a couple of weeks ago, we saw the Germans issued some preparatory legislation. So they're waiting for CRD IV to come into effect. And I think the UK also issued some transitional provisions for consultation.
所以他們正在準備CRD四，但對於這兩個司法管轄區來説，CRD四將是他們需要先生效的。正如我剛才所説，對於美國來説，他們已經宣佈了延遲，但他們非常謹慎地指出，他們非常認真地考慮了。
of their international timing commitments, and that they are working expeditiously to finalise the rulemaking process, but no firm timetable.
誒，我諗嚟基本上都已歸入前邊，我哋討論嘅就係都係關注啊。特別好多銀行都提過出嚟，誒，亦都透過書面咧，都大家都有啲感覺，就係有擔心，有誒唔一致實實施嘅時候咧，對香港有冇啲不利噉，所以咧就。
我建議係咪誒金管局或者政府方方面啊，提供一個誒？
我哋收集到嘅而家實施即係已經決定咗實施時間表嘅有關國家同地區，畀我哋作為其中一個參考嘅誒書面資料，喺稍後提供畀我哋。噉樣咧就亦都因為討論咗咁多啦，咁大家都相信將呢個關注咧已經交咗畀誒政府同埋監管當局咧。
留意啊，因為銀行界始終都係喺競爭當中咧，就擔心同國際上如果唔一致嘅時候，有冇咩啊可以引起咗香港不利嘅咧？咁嗱呢一點咧，我諗我哋已經記錄清楚喺度。咁如果我哋為咗唔即係唔阻礙到嗰個條例嘅審議，
咧，我就可以繼續進行，但係咧嗰個生效同埋點樣誒，即係所謂執行嗰方面咧，都請政府同埋監管當局咧再進一步再考慮一下。誒，有冇需要有啲乜嘢嘅誒做法，應抑或係繼續誒處理嘅時候咧，到時喺。
誒，所以實施嘅時間表上邊有冇咩其他嘅斟酌？
咁呢個就交由翻誒監管當局同埋政府再作誒你哋嘅研究，好唔好？噉我哋係啊，田田田長，主席好同意你嘅做法嘅。我哋可以審呢啲條例啦。嗯，不過可唔可能我哋考慮我哋用我哋嘅秘書處啊？嗯，就畀封信畀銀行。
誒工會呢度啊，就問問佢入邊嗰幾段先啊，我哋提出嚟，即係佢啲意思又好似有啲噉嘅含義，但係又好似唔係講得好清楚，或者佢哋可唔可以整復即係復下我哋啊？問佢呢度，或者你覺得係透過佢哋去問啊？誒復咗畀我哋咧，仲清楚啲咧？誒，我好同意梁家傑。
議員請話講清啱講嗰兩段啊，即係用咗個字眼imperative係好緊要啊，level regulatory playing field，跟住有個嘢叫做implement globally。嗯，但係globally佢冇話at the same time係咪即係globally，你你可以做遲幾年定係乜意思咧？咁可唔可以佢哋個封信啊，同我哋即係銀行公會同我哋復復咁？我唔知秘書處。
搞唔搞得掂？去問佢哋，要太過專家嘢，要透過佢哋幫手問問啦。誒，譬如你以為我哋可以發信請銀行公會嗰度咧，就作一啲澄清啦，關乎佢裏邊信裏邊提供嗰啲啦。特別係頭先有員講關於嗰個level playing field嗰個問題，或者提下關於EU同埋。
U.S.現金嗰個實施嗰個狀況啦，可以讀啲澄清嘅請工會。
噉我哋再補充一下呢方面，噉啊，我相信政府都已經誒，同埋監管當局都應該清楚咗我哋議員嘅關注㗎啦。
噉係咪我哋都唔會妨礙而家嘅審議再可以繼續進行？噉啊稍後嗰啲咧就再喺下下誒再稍後之後再補充，好冇？
誒，而家係請政府方面睇下。
對於繼續審議方面，你哋誒有咩？
建議今日誒有關嘅文件係。
請你哋介紹係邊方面嘅誒審議係開始繼續進行。啊，廖生，多謝主席。
喺上次誒十一月五號舉行嘅會議嗰度咧，啊咁委員咧要求政府咧再發一份文件畀委員會咧，就係誒解釋兩項事情嘅。咁誒第一項事情咧就係喺誒法例第一百五十五章附屬法例N銀行業指明多邊發展銀行。
公告啊，裡面第二條所指明嘅機構係咪有恰當嘅中文譯名啦？咁呢個上次有委員提到嘅，亦都誒有委員提到就係話請誒政府同埋金管局咧係預備一個啊一個文件，係解釋一下我哋現時嗰個二零一二年銀行業資本修訂規則同埋。
係巴塞爾協定三發出嗰個嘅資本標準嚟講咧，啊有啲乜嘢嘢主要修訂或者係商議之處，咁亦都請我哋解釋個點解我哋有噉嘅誒修訂咧，同埋要誒解釋一下銀行業就誒呢啲誒修訂嘅意見係點樣。咁誒就有關問題嘅兩部分，我哋就喺文件。
裡面已經説明啦，噉我先解誒簡介第一部分就係有關啊銀行業指明多邊發展銀行公告嗰個草擬嗰度。咁上次有委員咧就啊啊提出咧就係話誒喺誒誒喺審議嗰嗰份公告裡面咧，同時都發現咧原本嗰個現
行嗰個嘅銀行業指明多邊份發展銀行嘅公告咧，有一啲嘅多邊發展銀行嘅誒譯名咧，誒我哋係冇喺中文嘅文本度咧，係冇寫到嗰個中文名喺度嘅。咁誒，噉我呢度要解釋多次咧，就係誒，我哋今次嗰個修訂咧，個主要目的就係。
係落實巴塞爾啊委員會嗰個協定啦，就係將世銀集團其中之一個multilateral investment guarantee agency中文名就係多邊投資擔保機構咧，納入喺呢個公告底下嘅。咁上次好多謝委員有提出到，就係現行嗰個嘅中文法例裡面咧，誒有。
到一啲已經喺法例裡面嘅多邊發展銀行嘅英文咧，係冇直接咧係翻譯做中文嘅。噉我呢度咧都係諮詢過嚇律政司同事嘅意見啦嚇。現行嘅安排咧就冇特別影響到咧誒該條附屬法例有關嘅一個法律效力同埋運作。咁而亦都鑑於委員。
嘅意見啦，我哋亦都點討緊有關嘅條文，因為喺誒呢條條文誒，即係呢個公告咧，喺幾年前草擬嘅時候咧，我哋就冇發現到有關嘅機構嗰個中文嘅名稱。噉我哋而家咧就需要咧，特別係向誒呢啲多邊發展銀行再查明一下，佢哋有冇恰當嘅官方中文名稱。
咁委員都知道咧，誒，每一兩年咧，政府亦都會有一條咧係《成文法集項修訂嘅條例草案》，就係處理咧一係列呢一啲喺文本上嗰啲差異啊，或者係啲譯名啊嗰啲嘅問題嘅。噉我哋喺處理咗個檢討同埋個查詢之後咧，噉啊，政府係承諾咧會係第日喺適當嘅機會。
透過成文化集行修訂條例草案咧，係處理有關嘅啊嘅修訂噉樣。咁而今次我哋就誒覺得唔需要誒係誒影響咗而家嗰個立法嘅進度。多謝主席。
關於第二個有關嘅文本比較方面，係咪需要再啲誒説明咧？啊，係啊，主席啊，上次喺誒會議嘅時候咧，誒委員咧就誒亦都鑑於嗰個嘅誒個規則咧，嗰個份量都好啊沉重啦。噉就誒請政。
咧就誒預備一份文件，就係解釋一下誒誒，究竟誒巴塞爾協定三裏面規則同我哋而家立緊嗰個法例嗰個規則咧，有乜嘢主要嘅唔同，以方便咧委員係審議有關嘅誒即係規則嘅。噉我哋政府好樂意提供呢啲嘅資料。咁誒喺誒派畀議委員嘅。
文件裏面咧，誒亦都有個附件，就係用表列嘅形式咧，係解釋咗有關誒呢啲嘅規則，誒同巴塞爾協定有啲乜嘢嘢嘅分別。咁呢個就方便到議員即係誒逐誒cross by cross嗰個嘅審議嘅。噉我請金管局嘅同事就啊啊帶。
議員去審議有關嘅條文，多謝主席。好。
誒，講到先。
Thank you, Chairman. The main difference between the banking capital rules and Basel III is that Basel III will allow unrealised gains on property revaluation to be included within common equity tier one capital without limit.
The banking capital rules, in contrast, allow recognition only in tier two capital, with a fifty five percent haircut. So only forty five percent of property revaluation gains can be recognised, and only in the lower tier of capital. This reflects the existing.
situation under our existing capital rules in Hong Kong, and we have chosen to follow this route rather than adopt the Basel III standard, due largely to concerns about the historical volatility of prices of commercial property in Hong Kong. So our concern is that by allowing property revaluation gains into common equity.
Tier One， 我們會引入顯著的波動性到共同股權Tier One比率，這可能對銀行的支援或繼續放貸能力產生負面影響。如果未來有快速或顯著的不動產價格下跌，
The other deviations from Basel III are more minor. The next item concerns deferred tax assets and mortgage servicing rights.
These can be recognised within a threshold within the Basel III approach, but we do not propose to recognise them as capital under the banking capital rules.
Our reasons being that we we have reservations about the genuine loss absorption capacity of these items, so deferred tax assets.
For timing differences can only be reversed over time, so at best they represent future potential for reducing profits tax and increasing earnings. We don't think that that is capital. And mortgage servicing rights are created by capitalising future income streams from the servicing of mortgage loans which have been sold.
This is important in the United States, but they are not common in Hong Kong, and so we have no experience locally on which to found a judgement as to whether there would be continued availability of income from mortgage servicing rights to a bank in times of stress.
The third item in the table, Chairman, is what I would characterise as an anti-avoidance provision. Generally, capital instruments are deducted from capital under Basel III, but a capital investment, particularly if it were to be in a connected company, might be characterised as a loan.
It could be a perpetual loan, so we included a provision into the banking capital rules allowing the HKMA to recharacterise something like that as a capital investment if the lending institution cannot demonstrate that it's actually been incurred in the ordinary course of
business again, this largely reflects the existing position under the capital rules in Hong Kong.
係。
Chairman, Karen, I hope you no mind. You already went through three items. Could we stop here so we can have a discussion on that? Chairman, first, I like to declare my interest, as I am in the property business and I do borrow banks.
on some of the projects I do. Carol, on the first point you you mentioned.
你話：，Seeing under the new rule。
The 55% of unrealised.
嘅。
Of course, firstly.
I'm asking from the view of the borrower.
of the bank.
的。
一個developer that borrows money from the bank.
所以，你係講喺我嘅書，係被審計嘅。
if the property is worth so much, you're not saying 55% of that value. You're saying that if it's unrealised gain.
for example, if the property was bought for one million, and now it's worth one and half million, you're saying that one and half minus one, that five hundred thousand dollar gain.
你只係taking fifty five percent of that as a realised gain， and that would be allowable under the Basel three for the bank。
to take the value of my property and lend me according to that.
No, no, sorry. Maybe I've confused. So what is this fifty-five percent? So I may have confused the issue a bit. What we're looking at is property that's owned by the bank. So the bank is using it. It's either using it for its branches or no, the bank's own property. So if that's being revalued and the
Value is going up significantly, but they're unrealised gains in the sense that the bank hasn't sold the property, so it hasn't got the money. It's just got a paper gain. Then we are very nervous about allowing all of that paper gain into what will be the most important indicator of the bank's strength: common equity tier one capital. So we prefer to.
要去去去，跟住現狀做呢個，我們已經做咗，即係話，我們會認可百分之四十五嘅收益，所以百分之五十五唔計，我們會認可喺低級別嘅資本，即係第二級資本。所以唔同級別嘅資本有啲微差異嘅特性。
The tier one capital is regarded as going concern capital. It should be able to absorb losses and allow the bank to continue in business. Tier two capital is perhaps more gone concern capital, so it should absorb losses upon insolvency. But that's not much use for the bank to be able to continue in business. So
Generally speaking, what we propose to stick with the status quo and not allow unrealised property gains into common equity tier one.
主席，thank you for that clarification. So it's nothing to do with borrowers. But even in that scenario, I'm sorry because maybe in Hong Kong is too small. I have to use names. But let's say use HSBC. Their main building in Central might be built thirty years ago at this price, and now the revaluation might be three times.
of what's it worth? So you're saying the unrealised gain is what that's all that book.
所以for一new bank who just bought the building last year, then realise gain could be very small， and that fifty five percent might not mean much。 But if you take a bank like for example HSBC， the building， I'm sure the current market value maybe three four times of what they were originally bought at and the book cost。 So that would be a big haircut。
is is that what we're saying that we will do?
Yes, essentially, what we're saying is that.
As long as the gain remains unrealised, so I believe may have happened with property in the UK. If you sell and you you obtain the the funds, the money, then it becomes a realised gain. But as long as it remains unrealised, it doesn't get counted as common equity tier one capital for for
for the purposes of the capital rules, and certainly in turn affect
the borrowing power of that bank, because if that's not counted into capital, then the money they can lend up to SMEs or whatever in Hong Kong to personal mortgages, that would in proportion also be reduced because of
the safe the safe position of this unrealised gain, regardless of the cost, I could see the unrealised gain this one or two year. Well, it's not that much, but if the bank
had old building that would make a difference. And may I on the same point ask if the bank transfer the property to another subsidiary also wholly own, then you could be deemed as unrealised gain. We don't have capital gain tax, so the bank can do that, and then that all becomes a realised gain. Then are you saying that 55% will not apply?
就。
對。
We have an anti-avoidance.
provision。
Would that be considered anti-avoidance? Because you say unrealised gain, so I'm realising it. But but it's realised within the the same consolidation group. Okay, that's considered avoidance, which is the third part just talked about. Okay, but please comment. Are you saying that that should not, that could not be, they could not do that?
Well, we we we have a an anti-avoidance provision that would would would stop that because that that would just be realising the gain within the group. But there's no new money that that's actually coming to the group to support the group's lending.
所以，going forward， you you will see the。
因為佢係依啲係講緊重估嘅問題啊，所以呢個呢個咧就而家個準則即係將個百分率咧定定得比較保守啲喺香港，因為個flation比較大，所以咧純純粹喺個每一次嘅重估嗰度嚟到做一個誒，即係一個條界線咁解。所以我諗呢個咧就反為。
就唔同呢個mortgage嗰啲所謂collective一齊撈埋嚟計算嘅，嗰個就唔即係兩件兩件唔同嘅事。主席，佢佢用嘅英文詞唔係重估，unrealised gain係重估賺。佢佢佢係當係啊，佢將呢個差異咧就當係得到嘅機啊，但係實際上我哋係唔。
係，即係應該係完全重估嘅價值嚟啊！價值嘅重估啫。
O.K.，噉我哋都可以討論咗一下嘅。
誒係誒，先生，你要補充啊？Just for members' information and the anti-avoidance that Karen's referring to, in relation to a bank, as example given by Mr. Tin, is concerning, for example, a bank selling a property.
to subsidiaries and in such a way realise gain and that can is actually addressed by section 38.
subsection two D in the Basel three rules.
係，真係好多唔同嘅信息。
所以佢哋可以繼續啦，嗬。好。
哦，sorry。
Sorry. Yeah, the final, the final two fourth and fifth points are a rather technical.
點，relating to a formula for calculating something called a credit valuation adjustment capital charge. During the crisis, a lot of losses actually suffered by banks were not suffered from default of counterparties, but
Rather from the downgrading of counterparties, so the mark-to-market value of the contract with the counterparties fell because the counterparties were downgraded. So Basel III has introduced something called a credit valuation adjustment risk charge, so that banks will hold capital against that risk of mark-to-market losses.
但係，在計算。
this this charge.
You, you need to.
That banks need to map.
一個外部評級給對方，AAA、AA，或者什麼，來給一個權重給對方，這個權重然後再進入公式來計算CVA費用。我們做了兩個調整。
在這領域，第一個關係到一些歷史性的事。在一些授權機構的請求下，我們已經在銀行資本規則中承認了三間印度評級機構對印度公司的評級。
和Mapping。
那些Mapping external ratings to get the weight to go into the CVA calculation. We need to accommodate those Indian ECAI those Indian credit rating agency ratings, and we follow the Reserve Bank of India's mappings of those Indian ratings to obtain the credit quality grades.
necessary to assess the risk in the existing banking capital rules, and those are slightly different from the mapping of the international rating agencies like Moody's, Standard and Poor's, etc. So we have made an adjustment in the CVA calculation, just basically to reflect that difference that we are dealing with two sets of rating agencies.
國際評級機構和印度評級機構，和最後一點在點五是再沿著類似的線，對於決定適用於對方的權重來計算CVA費用，當對方沒有任何外部評級機構的評級時。
agency. Then under Basel III, there is a need to map a bank's internal rating to the external rating to get the weight. Now for banks that adopt the internal ratings-based system for calculating their regulatory capital, they obviously have internal ratings. Internal rating
based system， so they can map their internal ratings to the external ratings through a mapping scheme that's approved by us.
But for smaller banks that don't use the internal ratings based system, they're not IRB banks as we say. For simplicity, we've allowed them to assign a flat weight of 1%, which corresponds to a triple B rating. Now we we've done that because we think the 1% is a sort of reasonable cost.
Benefit analysis being sort of a fair, conservative approximation of what would be the average weight of a pool of counterparties. So it's to stop small banks having to develop a sort of a rating system so that they can have an internal rating to map to an external rating to get to get the weight for this particular calculation. So
所以我們去咗一個平一%，我們諮詢了業界關於呢個，業界已經表示呢個係可接受嘅。
所以係一啲。
OK。
噉啊，主要嘅差異已經誒，即係按照我哋上次嘅要求，就已經陳列咗頭先講嘅五五個五個主要點啦。
咁誒，主誒英文本嘅仲有誒，有冇需要嘅逐條條文嘅審議咧？
你哋誒冇追㗎啦，OK。冇錯，係多謝主席。
噉啊！
有關誒委員方面，對於誒，如果剛才講嘅政府誒，主要將嗰啲除咗差異嘅講之後咧，噉我哋誒按照正常情況底下咧，就英文嘅條文咧，頭先講所講就由政府方面同埋我哋嘅誒法律顧問都係進行個審議嘅。
噉我哋呢度咧就唔逐條去做㗎啦。
咁咧，如果喺個完成呢部分嘅審議之後咧，我哋就亦都會請誒助理法顧問咧，就條文嘅中文本方面嘅審議作一個簡報嘅。
咁咪咪請阿簡律師講講。
主席，咁個中文嘅修訂規則咧，我哋睇咗㗎啦。噉我哋就有啲某啲嘅誒草擬嘅問題，同政府係作出誒要求澄清嘅。咁政府都答咗我哋啦。噉我哋冇其他嘅問題，再會誒跟進嘅。
呃。
之後咧，我哋就想睇睇誒呢個成個立法時間表嗰方面啦，就想。
誒同大家誒講講就係審議期咧，就延展嘅時間咧，已經喺上次大會咧都誒向主席提咗，就係最遲就係十二月十二月嘅十二號，即係半年十二月十二號。
誒修訂附屬法例作預告嘅期限咧，就係五日五整天嘅咧，就係十二月五號叫做誒最後嘅預告。
而向內會作出報告日期咧，就係十一月嘅三十號。啊，呢三個日期咧，誒必須請大家。
都注意嘅。
咁咧就有關如果提出修正案咧，就係請大家留意，就係十二月五號必須之前提出。
咁亦都預告咧，就三十號咧由內會上邊咧就小組委員會會作出一個誒審議嘅報告。咁咧就呢度亦徵詢委員嘅意見，係是否同意本人以小組委員會主席嘅身份咧會喺內務委員會向大會提交。
有關研究法例及其文書嘅報告嘅議誒議案嘅辯論之中咧，進行發言嚟報告呢個委員會嘅審議工作。
誒係咪誒大家接受？
如果同意咧，我就會按照呢個時間表咧，就做做呢個有關安排。就請秘書處咧預留下段嘅時間咧，就睇下有冇需要，我哋仲係啦，會有啲書面啦，我哋會問工會啦，噉係點處理咧？係開會咧，還是係用傳熱形式？誒，想精。
傾下大家意見啦，因為正話有部分嘅文件，我哋都仲會同工會溝通。咁需唔需要會嘅方式，亦或係直接將文件送畀大家？冇意見嘅話咧，我就按剛才嘅時間表做嘢，就即係提供畀內會同埋大會啦。
係，誒送畀我哋O K㗎，誒會送畀大家得㗎啦，O K。咁如果噉嘅話咧，我諗我哋嘅總體審議咧就係到呢度為止㗎啦。咁咧就如果有特別嘅需要咧，我哋先至再會同大家即係溝通嘅。噉啊喺度我就多謝官員嘅出席，亦多謝我哋委員為呢個。
個審議做咗咁多工作。
多謝我哋嘅書書。
多謝主席。
誒，地會社去人民公園。